earthhourus.org 2009-09-18

# Earth Hour US

_Revised as of August 7, 2008_

Earth Hour US is a project of World Wildlife Fund US. Not only does WWF care about our planet, we care about online privacy. This privacy policy serves to inform you of what information we may collect about you, and how we may use that information. Please note that this privacy policy may change from time to time. 

Please read the following description of our privacy practices and, if you have any questions, visit our Help section, where you can view Frequently Asked Questions, submit a question via email and receive assistance from a WWF member services representative. You can also send a letter to:

Web Master-Earth Hour  
World Wildlife Fund  
1250 24th Street  
Washington, DC 20037 

### Table of Contents

I. What information may be collected  
II. How information may be used  
III. User control over collection and use of information

###  I. WHAT INFORMATION MAY BE COLLECTED

WWF collects two kinds of information: personal information that you choose to supply us, and non-personal information, such as your IP address. 

###  A. Personally Identifiable Information 

**Newsletters, Online Postcards, Donations and Other WWF Information**  
If you subscribe to a WWF e-newsletter, request additional information about WWF, submit a donation online, or participate in any of the other services on the WWF web site that require personal information, we may request your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address, birth year, and eligibility to vote, in order to respond to your inquiries. If you send a friend an online postcard, we may request your name and email address as well as the name and email address of the friend to whom you wish to send the postcard. WWF may collect and store the information you choose to provide us to send you information about WWF and WWF partners and third parties from time to time. If you make a donation to WWF and elect to pay online, WWF will collect the necessary financial information. WWF collects and stores some information the user chooses to provide, including name, address and email address, to send users information about WWF and WWF partners and third parties from time to time. WWF will not disclose financial information except as necessary to fulfill users' donation requests. WWF collects such financial information in a secure manner and discards such financial information after processing. 

Sweepstakes, Contests and Promotions  
From time to time, we may request information from you via online polls, surveys, sweepstakes or contests. Participation in these survey, sweepstakes or contests is completely voluntary; you have a choice whether or not to disclose information required to enter. Information requested may include personal contact information such as your name, shipping and email addresses. Contact information will be used to notify winners, award prizes and contact users with further information about WWF products and services, as well as the products and services of WWF partners and third parties. Survey information will be used for the purposes of monitoring or improving use and satisfaction of the WWF web site. 

Conservation Action Network  
WWF's Conservation Action Network (CAN) collects and uses personally identifiable information in connection with grassroots outreach and advocacy efforts. In order to use CAN's tools to send emails, faxes, or letters to decision makers, we require a user to provide a name, mailing address, and email address. Participation in CAN is entirely voluntary. Information collected is used for the promotion of WWF and CAN legislative goals, grassroots outreach and policy advocacy. 

Cookies  
A cookie is a piece of data placed on your hard drive when you visit our site. We may use cookies to help us recognize you when you come back to our site. We may also use cookies to help us monitor traffic on our site. This information may be aggregated in an anonymous manner. You can select to have our web site remember your email address and password on your specific computer when you login. This information will be stored in a cookie on your hard drive that will only be used when you return to the site to login again. 

We may from time to time link cookie information with personally identifiable information collected from the Conservation Action Network. This will help us better tailor our site and provide you with offers that we think may be of interest to you. 

### B. Non-personally identifiable information

Session Cookies  
A cookie is a piece of data placed on your hard drive when you visit our site. We use session cookies to help you navigate through the actions on our site when you log in, but they contain no personally identifiable information about you. We may also use cookies to help us monitor traffic on our site. This information may be aggregated in an anonymous manner. This will help us better tailor our site and provide you with offers that we think may be of interest to you. 

IP Addresses and Environmental Variables  
WWF may also collect information through IP addresses or environmental variables. An "IP address" is a number used by computers on the network to identify your computer so that data can be transmitted to you. "Environmental variables" include, among other things, the domain from which you access the Internet, the time you accessed our web site, type of web browser and operating system or platform used, the Internet address of the web site you left to visit WWF, the names of the pages you visit while at our web site, and the Internet address of the web site you then visit. We collect all of this information to allow us to detect broad demographic trends, to provide information tailored to your interests and to enhance your experience on websites operated by WWF. This information may be aggregated in an anonymous manner. 

### II. HOW INFORMATION MAY BE USED

We may share personally and non-personally identifiable information with third parties that help manage our web site and databases and with our partners and affiliates. We will not, however, share personally identifiable information obtained from activists when they subscribe to CAN or to send a message to a decision maker using CAN, with the following two exceptions: (1) when you take action, you will be identified on the action itself as the sender - for example, in the fax or email sent to the decision-maker; (2) we may share personally identifiable information with third parties that help manage our web site and databases, who are subject to a confidentiality agreement. 

### III. USER CONTROL OVER COLLECTION AND USE OF INFORMATION

WWF provides you with the following choices regarding the use of your information:  
You may set your browser to: (1) inform you when cookies are being set before a cookie is stored; (2) not accept cookies at all; and (3) erase all cookies from your hard drive. However, if you choose to reject or erase cookies, your ability to navigate our site may be limited. 

You may choose not to provide WWF with any contact information. However, if you do so, we will be unable to respond to your request for WWF information, enter you in any sweepstakes or contests, facilitate your action via CAN, or send online postcards. Additionally, your ability to navigate our site may be limited. 

If you would like to opt-out of receiving some or all further information from WWF, either (1) take the opportunity to opt out wherever personally identifiable information is collected, (2) take the opportunity to opt out in links on the bottom of email we send to you, or (3) go to the Profile Editor tool [www.worldwildlife.org/login](http://www.worldwildlife.org/login). 

If you would like to change or modify information you have previously provided us, please manage your profile by visiting our web site at [www.worldwildlife.org/login](http://www.worldwildlife.org/login). 

If you have any questions about this privacy policy or the practices of our Web sites, please contact: [membership@wwfus.org](mailto:membership@wwfus.org).
